

Technical Lead

J Upon Request

America/Central Timezone

skeg.dev

in kegdev

kegdev

@kegdeveops

Resume PDF

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Applied Science (BASc), Web Development Strayer University

Associate of Science (A.S.), Web Design ITT Technical Institute-Bessemer 2009 - 2011

LANGUAGES

English (Native)

CAREER PROFILE

Hi Y'all! "I'm a diligent and communicative senior web developer specializing in the Adobe Commerce platform. Locked and loaded with soft skills to match technical skills, with experience in work scenarios ranging from client-facing project leadership all the way to quality assurance.

EXPERIENCE

Technical Lead

Human Element - Ann Arbor, Michigan (remote)

October 2020 - Present

Primary Technical Lead with oversight and execution responsibilities of dozens of different projects on teams ranging from two to ten developers, along with accompanying project management, SEO and design resources. Experienced with deep dives into challenging integrations, complex front-end designs, as well as challenging clients.

Senior Magento Developer

August 2020 - October 2020

Human Element - Ann Arbor, Michigan (remote)

Joined the Human Element team as a Senior Web Developer with experience in front-end and back-end Adobe Commerce development.

Web Development Team Lead

April 2019 - Aug 2020

EBSCO Industries, Inc. - Birmingham, AL

Facilitates team activities while mentoring web developers and handling a healthy work load of projects. Primarily Wordpress, Magento 1.x/2.x, PWA development in addition to qualifications of previous positions.

Web Development Team Lead

April 2019 - August 2020

EBSCO Industries, Inc. - Birmingham, AL

Facilitates team activities while mentoring web developers and handling a healthy work load of projects. Primarily Wordpress, Magento 1.x/2.x, PWA development in addition to qualifications of previous positions.

Senior Magento PHP Developer

April 2016 - April 2019

EBSCO Industries, Inc. - Birmingham, AL

Seasoned Full-Stack Magento Web Developer with 5+ years of focus on the Enterprise version. Created highly-customized client-specific extensions for robust subscription renewals and IBM Mainframe integration via flat-file transfer. Responsible for much of the team's developmental decision workflow and implementation of projects. Actively work as an enthusiastic platform evangelist and mentor to fellow Magento developers.

Magento PHP Developer

April 2013 - April 2016

EBSCO Industries, Inc. - Birmingham, AL

Worked on Magento 1.x Enterprise edition to contribute as a primary development asset on over a dozen websites across multiple installations.

Software Quality Assurance Engineer

Oct 2007 - Apr 2013

EBSCO Industries, Inc. - Birmingham, AL

General QA testing and software quality assurance on .ASP and .NET-based projects.

SKILLS & PROFICIENCY

